# Anuj Pandit Patil, Senior Software Engineer

Pune, India, 9730482383, anujpatil358@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Accomplished Senior Software Engineer with 4 years of experience leading projects by acting as the architect, developer, and programmer analyst. Proficient at supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. A strong leader capable of guiding support teams and solving complex issues. Steadfast in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industry best practices.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Oct 2021 — Present

### Senior Software Developer, Tech Prescient

Pune / Remote

- As a Python developer, Worked on client-side projFeedbackects. With the help of Django Framework and PostgreSQL database.
- Have experience with different AWS services such as AWS Lambda, API Gateway, EC2, and Cloudwatch.
- Designed the database architecture for a Role Based Access Control system which uses the Python Flask framework and MySQL databases with SQL Alchemy ORM.
- · Management of the team's performance and daily activities as a scrum master.
- · As the lead developer, Was responsible for ensuring all backend code was error-free.

#### Jun 2021 — Oct 2021

## Software Developer, NeoSOFT technologies

Pune / Remote

- · Consistently deliver features using Agile methodologies.
- Provided features by collaborating with the Product team on Requirements Analysis, creating approach documentation and data flow diagrams, as well as writing clear unit-test cases.
- A number of scalable Rest APIs have been developed on the portal that is available to customers.

### May 2019 — Jun 2021

## Python Developer, Leo Coders

Nagpur

- Involved in end-to-end software design and development including requirement gathering, documentation, architecture design, programming, and testing.
- Successfully worked at an independent level, while also serving as an effective Counselled.
- Designed database architecture, backend logic, and REST APIs for my key project Dualingua, PMS (Property Management System), LifeHomeMatch in Python using Django framework as backend, MySql database with ORM.
- · The entire backend falls under my responsibility.
- · Provided informational input into the development plans for applications, programs, and systems.

SKI	TI	S

Python	Expert	PhpMyAdmin	Experienced
Django	Experienced	ORM	Experienced
Flask	Experienced	SQL	Experienced
OOP's	Expert	GitHub	Expert
Postgresql	Experienced	HTML/CSS/JavaScript	Experienced
MySQL	Experienced	jQuery	Experienced
Docker	Experienced	NoSQL	Skillful
Pandas	Skillful		

#### **EDUCATION**

Jun 2014 — Nov 2019

### Bachelor of Engineering, Nagpur University

Wardha Completed Bachelor of Engineering from Rashtrasant Tukadoji Maharaj Nagpur university.

### CERTIFICATION

- Python
- Django

LINKS

## linkedin, GitHub, Online Resume

### TECHNICAL

- Focus on code quality and reusability.
- Reviewed colleague's codes, highlighted any discrepancies and brought them to their attention.
- Write code that follows all oops concepts
- Experienced with specific technologies like Flask, Sqlalchemy, Mysql, AWS, Jira, Slack, Git, Pycharm, VS Code, Linux, React, OOP's, DataStructure and Algorithm, Unit testing etc.
- Isort and flake8 is used to monitor good quality of code.